[
  {
    "question": "Это делаем меня грустным",
    "answer": "It makes me sad",
    "tasks": ["makes", "sad"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я очень раздражен этим",
    "answer": "I am very annoyed by this",
    "tasks": ["annoyed", "by"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Эта картина меня вдохновляет",
    "answer": "This picture inspires me",
    "tasks": ["inspires"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Мне нужно немного времени, чтобы разобраться с лучшим решением этой проблемы",
    "answer": "I need some time to figure out the best solution to this problem",
    "tasks": ["need", "some", "to", "figure", "out", "solution"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я потерял свой кошелек на тротуаре",
    "answer": "I lost my wallet on the pavement",
    "tasks": ["pavement"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Мне все равно",
    "answer": "I don't care",
    "tasks": ["I", "don't", "care"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Это зависит от тебя",
    "answer": "It's up to you",
    "tasks": ["It's", "up", "to", "you"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Как она выглядит?",
    "answer": "What does she look like ?",
    "tasks": ["What", "does", "she", "look", "like"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Какой у него характер?",
    "answer": "What is he like ?",
    "tasks": ["What", "is", "he", "like"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Какой он? (город)",
    "answer": "What is it like ?",
    "tasks": ["What", "is", "it", "like"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Давай пойдем на этот холм",
    "answer": "Let's go to this hill",
    "tasks": ["hill"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я хочу посмотреть ратушу",
    "answer": "I want to see a town hall",
    "tasks": ["town", "hall"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Наш корабль приходит в гавань",
    "answer": "Our ship comes to a harbour",
    "tasks": ["harbour"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Это еще не ясно",
    "answer": "It's not clear yet",
    "tasks": ["It's", "not", "clear", "yet"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Мы узнали, кто был убийцей",
    "answer": "We found out who was a killer",
    "tasks": ["found", "out"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я не люблю молочные продукты",
    "answer": "I don't like dairy",
    "tasks": ["dairy"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я никогда не пью газировку",
    "answer": "I never drink fizzy",
    "tasks": ["fizzy"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я разбил кувшин",
    "answer": "I broke the jug",
    "tasks": ["jug"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Они разделили второе место",
    "answer": "They joint second place",
    "tasks": ["joint"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Это противоречит нашим правилам",
    "answer": "It contradicts our rules",
    "tasks": ["contradicts"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Получается вкусно",
    "answer": "It turned out delicious",
    "tasks": ["It", "turned", "out"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я снижаю риск болезни",
    "answer": "I reduce the risk of illness",
    "tasks": ["reduce"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Кофе не дает вам заснуть",
    "answer": "Сoffee keeps you awake",
    "tasks": ["keeps", "you", "awake"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я не очень люблю бегать",
    "answer": "I'm not keen on running",
    "tasks": ["keen", "on"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Давай, не отставай",
    "answer": "Come on, keep up",
    "tasks": ["Come", "on", "keep", "up"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я в хорошей форме",
    "answer": "I'm in good shape",
    "tasks": ["in", "good", "shape"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я поддерживаю форму",
    "answer": "I keep fit",
    "tasks": ["keep", "fit"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я останусь здесь еще на 3 недели",
    "answer": "I stay here for another 3 weeks",
    "tasks": ["for", "another"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Почему бы тебе не купить ей цветы?",
    "answer": "Why don't you buy her some flowers?",
    "tasks": ["Why", "don't", "you"]
  },
  {
    "question": "79c",
    "answer": "seventy-nine cents",
    "tasks": ["seventy-nine", "cents"]
  },
  {
    "question": "59p",
    "answer": "fifty-nine pence",
    "tasks": ["fifty-nine", "pence"]
  },
  {
    "question": "€10.55",
    "answer": "ten euros fifty-five",
    "tasks": ["ten", "euros", "fifty-five"]
  },
  {
    "question": "£3.27",
    "answer": "three pounds twenty-seven",
    "tasks": ["three", "pounds", "twenty-seven"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Примерь эту футболку",
    "answer": "Try on this t-short",
    "tasks": ["Try", "on"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Можем ли мы сделать это немного позже?",
    "answer": "Сan we make it a bit later ?",
    "tasks": ["Сan", "we", "make", "it", "a", "bit", "later"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ты знаешь, собрания",
    "answer": "You know , meetings",
    "tasks": ["You", "know"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Давай сделаем это в 7",
    "answer": "Let's make it seven",
    "tasks": ["Let's", "make", "it"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Он часто хвалит своего ребенка",
    "answer": "He often praises his child",
    "tasks": ["praises"]
  },
  {
    "question": "У тебя был хороший день?",
    "answer": "Have you had a good day ?",
    "tasks": ["Have", "you", "had", "a", "good", "day"]
  },
  {
    "question": "А ты?",
    "answer": "What about you ?",
    "tasks": ["What", "about", "you"]
  },
  {
    "question": "В какое время?",
    "answer": "What time ?",
    "tasks": ["What", "time"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Подойдет ли это вам? (Про время)",
    "answer": "Will it work for you ?",
    "tasks": ["Will", "it", "work", "for", "you"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я бы с удовольствием приготовил завтрак для тебя",
    "answer": "I would love to cook breakfast for you",
    "tasks": ["I", "would", "love", "to", "cook"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ой, извини, продолжай",
    "answer": "Oh sorry , go on",
    "tasks": ["sorry", "go", "on"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Мне кажется, моя собака толстая",
    "answer": "It seems to me my dog is fat",
    "tasks": ["It", "seems", "to", "me"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Он занял у меня деньги",
    "answer": "He borrowed money from me",
    "tasks": ["borrowed", "money", "from", "me"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я одалживаю ему деньги",
    "answer": "I lend money to him",
    "tasks": ["lend", "money", "to", "him"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я обычно теряю ключи",
    "answer": "I usually lose my keys",
    "tasks": ["lose"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я сдал экзамен",
    "answer": "I passed on exam",
    "tasks": ["passed", "on"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я провалил экзамен",
    "answer": "I failed on exam",
    "tasks": ["failed", "on"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я приеду в 6",
    "answer": "I'll arrive at 6",
    "tasks": ["I'll", "arrive", "at"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я уйду в 10",
    "answer": "I'll leave at 10",
    "tasks": ["I'll", "leave", "at"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я починю твои очки",
    "answer": "I'll mend your glasses",
    "tasks": ["I'll", "mend"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Если побежим, то успеем на поезд в 6.14",
    "answer": "If we run, we can catch the 6.14 train",
    "tasks": ["catch"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Если не побежим, то опоздаем на поезд в 5",
    "answer": "If we don't run, we miss the 5 train",
    "tasks": ["miss"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я собираюсь на станцию забрать Тима",
    "answer": "I'm going to station to pick up Tim",
    "tasks": ["pick", "up"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я собираюсь на станцию высадить Тима",
    "answer": "I'm going to station to drop off Tim",
    "tasks": ["drop", "off"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Она попросила его приготовить ужин",
    "answer": "She asked him for cook dinner",
    "tasks": ["asked", "for"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я сомневаюсь в этом",
    "answer": "I doubt it",
    "tasks": ["I", "doubt", "it"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Этот фильм был отстой",
    "answer": "This film was suck",
    "tasks": ["suck"]
  },
  {
    "question": "айфон прослужит много времени",
    "answer": "iPhone will serve a lot of time",
    "tasks": ["serve"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я обычно побеждаю в шахматах",
    "answer": "I usually defeat at chess",
    "tasks": ["defeat"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Я ем обычный хлеб",
    "answer": "I eat usual bread",
    "tasks": ["usual"]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "answer": "",
    "tasks": [""]
  }
]
